Hello English learners and welcome
to English Pod, my name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
Hey, Erica, who are you today?
Marco, I am doing really well and I'm
really looking forward to today's lesson.
Well, so am I, because here at English
Pod, we're giving you real English.
Every day English.
Exactly English that you
hear in movies or in TV shows.
This is English people actually use.
So, Erica, what is our topic for today?
Well, today we're talking
about computer viruses.
Perfect.
So, I think it's time for us
to take a look at our preview.
Very cabaret-y preview.
Okay, today we've got two words to preview.
The first word is virus.
Virus.
So, if your computer has a computer virus,
it means your computer's sick, right?
Actually, a computer
virus is a program that
is designed to harm or
to damage your computer.
Oh, I see.
Okay.
Well, thank you for being so technical.
That's the technical explanation.
Okay, let's take a look at our
second word for our preview today.
And that would be
froze, froze, froze, froze.
So if your computer froze, it means
that your computer stopped working.
Your applications or your programs stopped
working and you just can't do anything.
Your computer's broken.
Okay, great.
So, let's listen to our dialogue.
It's going to be a
little bit fast, but don't
worry if you don't
understand everything.
At the end of this podcast,
you'll understand everything.
Perfect.
Let's listen.
Alright, the stupid computer froze again.
That's the third time today.
Hey, Samuel, can you come take a
look at my PC, it's acting up again.
Let's have a virus or something.
Just give me a second, I'll be right up.
I ran a virus scan on
your computer and it
turns out that you have
a lot of infected files.
But I'm quite careful when
I'm browsing the internet.
I have no idea how I could
have picked up a virus.
Well, you have to make sure there are
antivirus softwares updated regularly.
Yours wasn't up to date, that's
probably what was causing your problems.
Okay.
Anything else?
Yeah.
Try not to kick or hit the computer.
Yeah, sorry about that.
Well, I completely understand this guy.
When my computer freezes, I kick it
and punch it and do everything to it.
Well, I hope you don't
punch it too hard, Marko.
Well, it's still working, so it's alright.
Okay.
Alright, let's take a look
at our language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
In today's language
takeaway, we have two words.
The first word for today
is infected file infected
file infected file and
what is an infected file?
An infected file is a file in your
computer that has a virus in it.
Ah, perfect.
That's really clear.
What is our second word for
the language takeaway today?
Our second word is not up to
date, not up to date, not up to date.
And what is it when
something is not up to date?
It means it doesn't have all
the most recent information.
Okay.
Perfect.
Now let's listen to some examples.
I need to buy a new computer
because mine isn't up to date.
Example two.
I can't find the street.
Are you sure this map is up to date?
Pull three.
Sarah has just finished the reports
and all the information is up to date.
Okay.
That was pretty clear.
You know, you can also
use this phrase positively.
You can say up to date.
Okay.
For example, we can say this is a new map.
This is the most up to date map.
Exactly.
Or if I bought a new computer, I could say.
I just got a new computer.
All my software is up to date.
Okay.
Great.
So now let's take a look at some phrases.
And it's time for putting it all together.
Put it in it together.
Okay.
So Samuel said a really great phrase.
He said I'll be right up.
I'll be right up.
Now we can use this phrase
in a lot of different situations.
So let's listen to some examples.
Example one.
Can you help me with my computer?
I'll be right there.
Example two.
Come downstairs.
Dinner is ready.
I'll be right down.
Example three.
Hurry up.
I need to use the bathroom.
I'll be right out.
Okay.
Really great and clear examples, right?
Yeah.
You know that phrase?
I'll be right out.
I used to hear this all the
time when I was young.
Really?
How come?
Well, I have two sisters and we
were always fighting for the bathroom.
So someone was always saying,
just a minute, I'll be right out.
Ah, yes.
That's common.
I had that too.
And when I was young.
Now our second
phrase is it turns out that
it turns out that it turns out that it
turns out that this is a great phrase.
You can use it in many
different situations.
Marco, can you give us an example?
Sure.
For example, I can say,
Frank didn't come to
work today and it turns
out that he was sick.
Yep.
Or I could say, oh, I've been
feeling really sick recently.
Why?
It turns out that I'm pregnant.
Oh my God.
Are you really pregnant?
No, I'm not.
I'm just kidding.
All right.
Because, okay.
So it's time for us to
listen to our dialogue again.
But this time it'll be a little bit slower.
All right.
Oh, great.
This stupid computer froze again.
That's the third time today.
Hey, Samuel.
Can you come take a look at my PC?
It's acting up again.
It must have a virus or something.
Just give me a second.
I'll be right up.
I ran a virus scan on
your computer and it
turns out that you have
a lot of infected files.
But I'm quite careful when
I'm browsing the internet.
I have no idea how I could
have picked up a virus.
Well, you have to make sure that your
antivirus software is updated regularly.
Yours wasn't up to date.
That's probably what was
causing your problems.
Okay.
Anything else?
Yeah.
Try not to kick or hit the computer.
Oh, yeah.
Sorry about that.
Okay.
That was a lot more clear this time.
Definitely.
Yeah.
I understood a lot more.
Okay.
So now it's time to
look at fluency builder.
Erica, why don't you explain
what fluency builder is?
Influency builder, we
give you some great,
useful phrases to help you
express your ideas clearly.
Okay.
Great.
So let's look at fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay.
So in this dialogue, we know
his computer wasn't working.
Right.
So many students would probably
say his computer was acting strangely.
His computer isn't working properly.
Exactly.
And that's perfect.
And that's fine.
Yeah.
But there's a really great way to
say it that we heard in the dialogue.
It's acting up again.
I love this phrase.
It's acting up.
Yeah.
It just sounds really natural.
Okay.
We're ready to listen
to our dialogue a third
time, but this time it'll
be at the normal speed.
Try and see if you can hear these keywords.
Oh great, the stupid computer for us again.
That's a third time today.
Hey, Samuel.
Can you come take a look at my PC?
It's acting up again.
Let's have a virus or something.
Just give me a second.
I'll be right up.
I ran a virus scan on your computer
and it turns out that you have a lot of
infected files, but I'm quite careful
when I'm browsing the internet.
I have no idea how I could
have picked up a virus.
Well, you have to make sure there are
antivirus software is updated regularly.
Yours wasn't up to date.
That's probably what was
causing your problems.
Okay.
Anything else?
Yeah.
Try not to kick or hit the computer.
Um, yeah.
Sorry about that.
So Marco, I really think that my
computer actually has a virus now.
Really?
How come?
Because I have been turning on my
computer and then suddenly it turns off by
itself.
It shuts down by itself.
Yeah.
That sounds like a virus.
But I ran a virus scan
and there was no problem.
Well, maybe your antivirus
software isn't up to date.
Yeah.
I guess I'd better call Samuel.
You can call Samuel to fix it.
Yeah.
A lot of time now.
But be sure to go to our
website at englishpod.
com where you can leave all
your questions and comments.
So stay tuned for our next
great lesson and until next time.
Goodbye.
Bye.